congrats you didn't give up you made it
祝贺你没有放弃 你成功了
to part four you clicked on the next
在第四部分中 您点击了下一个
part of the video there's always like
视频的一部分总是像这样
less viewers each uh video as you go
更少的观众 每个视频 你走
down so you're here well done thumbs up
向下所以你在这里做得好竖起大拇指
um as you can tell by the title of this
嗯 正如你可以从这本书的标题中看出的
video we're going to learn about
我们将要了解的视频
sculpting but first I should call out uh
雕刻 但首先我要喊出来 嗯
if you have a problem with your mesh now
如果您现在的网状结构有问题
those problems can be Amplified the
这些问题可能会被放大
further you go along so it helps to do a
再往前走 这样做会对你有帮助
technical check now make sure you don't
现在进行技术检查 确保您不会
have any problems before we move along
在我们继续前行之前有什么问题吗
so to look for it go into edit mode um
所以要查找它 请进入编辑模式
and first of all by the way if you can't
首先 顺便说一句 如果你不能
see that middle party of mesh it's
看到那个中间的网状结构了吗
because you remember we temporarily hit
因为你还记得我们曾短暂地
it so you can bring it back by hitting
这样你就可以通过点击把它带回来
alt H and that will uh bring back the
Alt H 这将呃带回
rest of the mesh and then we're looking
剩下的网状物 然后我们在寻找
for issues with the mesh like right here
有关网格的问题 请参见此处
so this is a really common problem
所以这是一个非常常见的问题
following this tutorial because when
遵循本教程 因为当
you're projecting parts of the mesh if
如果您投影的是网格的某些部分
it was like side onto the camera it will
它就像镜头的侧面 它会的
project it that way and then you can
以这种方式投射 然后你就可以
have like overlapping parts of the mesh
具有类似重叠的网格部分
so that creates this artifact here which
这就产生了这个艺术品 它
will be exaggerated when we add more
当我们添加更多时会被夸大
detail to it so we just want to drag
它的细节 所以我们只想拖
that back so turn on on snapping and
背面 所以打开捕捉和
I'll keep proportional turned off and
我将保持比例关闭 并
then I'm just going to move this back
那我就把这个搬回去
over here just to move each of these
到这里来只是为了把这些都搬过来
points back um another very common
向后指 嗯 另一个非常常见的
problem is you might have parts that
问题是你可能有一些零件
have separated uh from your mesh now you
已经从你的网中分离了 嗯 现在你
can quickly fix this if you just like
如果您喜欢 可以快速修复此问题
selected the point and then T sorry hit
选中该点 然后按下T对不起
G to move it when you're in that state
当你处于那种状态时 G来移动它
it's also snapping it to the mesh now
它现在也在将其捕捉到网格上
you could do that all the way along like
你可以像这样一直这样做
select tap G then click select tap G
选择TAP G 然后单击选择TAP G
then click but that's
然后点击 但那是
anybody's got time for that let's make
任何人都有时间 让我们一起做吧
blend to do the work for us so there's a
混合为我们做这项工作 所以有一个
tool that's just designed for this and
专门为此而设计的工具
it's called the shrink wrap modifier so
它被称为收缩包装修改器 所以
over to our trusty modifier stack we're
转到我们值得信赖的修改器堆栈 我们
going to add yet another modifier so add
我要添加另一个修饰符 所以添加
modifier it's not under generate it's
修饰符它不在生成下面 它是
under deform which we haven't accessed
在我们尚未访问的Deform下
before new modifiers oo the one we're
在新的修饰物出现之前
looking for is shrink wrap and first of
寻找的是收缩包装和第一个
all hasn't done anything because uh it's
都没有做任何事情 因为呃 它是
f it needs to know what the target is
如果它需要知道目标是什么
what is the mesh that we're shrink
我们正在收缩的网状结构是什么
wrapping our um mesh too so with this
包裹我们的这个网眼也是这样的
little eyedropper tool you can see when
小吸管工具 您可以看到何时
you've clicked it my curs has changed to
你点击了 我的古董们变成了
an eyedropper and it now if I hover over
一支滴管 如果我悬停在它上面
objects I got the name of it so I want
我得到了它的名字 所以我想
to click on the object that is the dut
要单击作为DUT的对象
and now it's snapped to the donut and
现在它被卡在甜甜圈上了
made it worse why Andrew would you make
更糟糕的是 为什么安德鲁会让
us do that remember the order of your
我们这样做 记住你的顺序
modifier stack matters so the reason
修改器堆栈很重要 所以原因
this happened is because we've done it
发生这件事是因为我们做了
after the solidifier M it works top toot
在固化剂M之后 它工作在最上面的嘟嘟声
bottom we want the strink wrap to happen
最后 我们希望链条缠绕发生
before any of the Extrusion happens so
在任何一次挤压发生之前
now that it's there it's correct and
现在它在那里了 它是正确的
this is what it looks like before and
这是它之前的样子 而且
this is after and it's subtle right and
这是在之后 这是微妙的正确和
you'll probably see this across your
你可能会在你的
mess like little subtle changes where
一团糟就像是细微的变化
maybe it just separated off the mesh
也许它只是从网状结构中分离出来
which wasn't quite a perfect alignment
这并不是一条完美的路线
but this will just correct that so great
但这将纠正这一点 太棒了
we don't need this here now we can just
我们这里不需要这个 现在我们可以
apply it because it was just a once- off
应用它 因为它只是一次
operation and now all our mesh should be
现在我们所有的网状物都应该
perfectly flat and assuming you haven't
完全平淡 假设你没有
got any other issues going on uh again
有没有什么其他问题 呃 又来了？
make sure you use my Discord if you do
如果你这样做了 一定要利用我的不和
have issues and you need someone to help
有问题 你需要有人帮助
um make use of the community so use that
嗯 利用这个社区 所以用那个
and post your problem and I'm sure
把你的问题发布出来 我相信
people can help out all right so we want
人们可以帮助我们 所以我们希望
to do some sculpting now why do we want
现在做一些雕刻 为什么我们要
a sculpt well because if you look at
雕刻得很好 因为如果你看
reference photos of um donuts with icing
参考图片：糖衣甜甜圈
on them you'll see that icing is
在它们上面你会看到糖霜是
obviously a liquid and liquid does weird
显然 液体和液体会变得很奇怪
things one of the weird things that it
奇怪的事情之一就是它
does is that it will pull in certain
所做的就是它会吸引某些人
areas it's not like a uniform amount all
地区不像是一个统一的数量
the way on it so the most obvious being
所以最明显的就是
like at the end of this Trail here there
就像在这条小路的尽头
would be more that would accumulate at
将会有更多的积累
the end there and I think the reason for
结束在那里 我认为原因是
it is that because it's a viscous fluid
因为它是一种粘性流体
once it runs out of enough fluid there's
一旦它用完了足够的液体
not enough to kind of push it forward
不足以推动它向前发展
but there's enough for it to build up so
但有足够的东西让它积聚起来
you would have like a buildup here on
你会想要在这里集结一下
each of these ends but you would also
每一个都会结束 但你也会
have buildups all along the edge and you
在边缘都有积聚 你
can see it in reference photos like here
可以在参考照片中看到它 比如这里
we've got this like clear um was it like
我们把这个弄清楚了 嗯 是不是像这样
a glaze and basically the area there
一种釉面 基本上是那里的区域
where it looks whiter that's a thickened
在看起来更白的地方 这是一个加厚的
area so we essentially want to replicate
所以我们本质上想要复制
that across our donut so we can't do
在我们的甜甜圈上所以我们不能
that currently like if you go into edit
现在 如果你进入编辑模式
mode we don't have any mesh to work with
我们没有任何网格可用的模式
cuz the Extrusion the thickened part is
因为挤压加厚的部分是
happening via this modifier so we need
通过这个修饰符发生 所以我们需要
to make the modifier real so again we're
让修饰语变得真实 所以我们再一次
just going to apply it drop down apply
只是要应用它下拉应用
now in edit mode we have that part of
现在在编辑模式中 我们有该部分
the mesh to work with so um we could if
要使用的网格 所以 如果我们可以
you wanted to come in here and like
你想来这里然后就像
select SCT the points that you want to
选择SCT您想要的点
add you know a bulge to and then very
加上你知道的凸起 然后非常
carefully come in and tap G and then oh
小心地进来 轻敲G 然后哦
I've got snapping turned on turn that
我已经打开了捕捉功能打开那个
off uh pull this out right and go like
出发 呃 把这个拿出来 然后像这样
that and go yep there's a little bulge
然后走吧 是的 有一个小凸起
there but that's very tedious to First
有 但这是非常乏味的第一次
select a point then tap a key to move it
选择一个点 然后轻触一个键来移动它
it's it's very tedious so that's really
这是非常乏味的 所以这真的是
like you just need to use another tool
就像你只需要使用另一种工具
to do the job so edit mode is one tool
要完成这项工作 编辑模式是一种工具
and it's it's it's good for like very
而且它对非常好的
precise things when you need to get
当你需要得到的时候 精确的东西
precise things but for more more like
精准的东西 但更像
organic shapes more freehand stuff
有机造型更写意的东西
that's where sculpting comes in So at
这就是雕塑的用武之地
the top here we've just been flipping
我们刚刚翻转的上衣
between object and edit mode but the one
在对象模式和编辑模式之间切换 但
underneath it is sculpt mode so when we
它下面是雕刻模式 所以当我们
go into that mode you'll see that we
进入该模式 您将看到我们
have on the left hand side all of these
在左手边有所有这些
tools that appear and I mean this isn't
出现的工具 我是说 这不是
a sculpting like tutorial really um
像雕刻这样的教程真的很嗯
we're just really going to scratch the
我们真的要把
surface but they do different things um
表面上看 但他们做了不同的事情
different sculpting things like let's
不同的雕塑 比如让我们
just use the default tool here can't
仅使用此处的默认工具不能
relase see much happen let's just turn
再看一眼发生的事 让我们转身
up the strength and the size of it like
加大它的强度和大小 就像
it just pulls out that part of it and
它只是把那部分拉出来 然后
even that quick little one stroke
即使是那个快速的小划水
imagine if you had to select each of
想象一下 如果你必须选择每一个
those points and pull them out one by
然后把它们一个接一个地拉出来
one like that's why this tool is the
这就是为什么这个工具是
appropriate tool for this kind of job
适用于这类工作的工具
right because it's just very quickly
对 因为它只是非常快
going to enable us to add lots of
这将使我们能够添加大量
complex shape very cool so uh the tool
复杂的形状非常酷 所以呃这个工具
that we're looking for is actually it's
我们要找的实际上是
this one the inflate brush which is just
这把充气刷子就是
uh conveniently the I hotkey
呃 方便地按下I热键
inflate by the way uh if you want to
顺便说一句 呃 如果你想的话
change the size of brushes in uh blender
改变搅拌机中刷子的大小
I mean you've got these ones here you've
我的意思是 你有这些 你有
also got the strength slider here but
也有力量滑块在这里 但是
there is a hot key uh just to change the
有一个热键 呃 只是为了改变
size of the brush with f so F to change
画笔的大小与f相同 因此F要更改
the the size of the brush um and you
刷子的大小嗯和你
just pull out with your cursor to make
只需用光标拉出即可
it bigger and then pull in to uh reduce
它变大了 然后停下来 呃 缩小
it and then do a single left click to
然后单击鼠标左键即可
confirm you can also change the strength
确认你也可以改变力量
with shift F so shift F pull out click
使用Shift F 因此Shift F拉出 单击
and then shift F pull in in click um
然后按Shift键将其拉入Click Um
anyways so if I was to uh draw on this
不管怎样 如果我要呃利用这一点
you can see that I'm inflating that edge
你可以看到我在把边缘充气
I could also inflate here but you very
我也可以在这里充气 但你非常
quickly realize like look at that look
很快就意识到了 就像看着那个样子
at that what is that right the eye is
在那右眼是什么？
going to see that um it's a pro tip your
去看看 嗯 这是个职业小费
ey is uh like if you're going low res
EY 呃 就像你要去低分辨率
don't go low res for things that are
不要对那些低分辨率的东西
round because your eye is very quickly
圆圆的 因为你的眼睛很快
going to spot uh low poly things
去发现 呃 低聚物
actually just last night I was playing
实际上 就在昨晚 我在演奏
uh Spider-Man the Miles Morales one and
嗯 蜘蛛侠和迈尔斯·莫拉莱斯一号
uh there was like this coffee cup that
呃 有一个咖啡杯
was on a table and then you walk and it
在桌子上 然后你走了 它
looks fine like has a a background asset
看起来不错 像是有背景的资产
but then part of it the mission you had
但其中的一部分是你的任务
to go up and read something on the table
上去看看桌上的东西
and you had to get close to this coffee
你必须靠近这杯咖啡
top uh coffee cup and it was like eight
最上面的 呃 咖啡杯 好像是八个
vertices it just look like a almost look
顶点它看起来就像是一个近乎
like a nut on a wheel of a car right
就像汽车轮子上的螺母一样 对吗？
just like that Jagged so anyways what
就像那样 锯齿状 那又怎样？
I'm saying is this is a rounded form so
我是说 这是一个圆形 所以
we need more information we need more
我们需要更多的信息我们需要更多
detail uh to sculpt on the reason this
细节上呢就是雕刻这个原因
is Jagged and the reason there's not
是锯齿状的 而不是
enough detail here is that just even
这里足够详细的是 即使
though we have a subsurf modifier a
虽然我们有一个潜水修改器
subdivision modifier um it's applying it
细分修改器 它正在应用它
after we do the sculpt mode so when
在我们完成雕刻模式之后 当
you're in sculpt mode it's still just
你现在处于造型模式 它仍然只是
using your uh your raw mesh here and
在这里使用你的 呃 你的原始网格
then it does this as a secondary step so
然后 它将此作为次要步骤执行 因此
if we want to sculpt into this detail we
如果我们想要雕刻成这个细节 我们
need to apply this so um I actually I'm
我需要涂抹这个 所以我实际上我
going to use more than one I'm going to
我要用的不止一个 我要
use two cuz I want to have even more
用两个 因为我想要更多
detail so uh um importantly by the way
顺便说一句 细节 呃 很重要
if you're applying a subdivision
如果要应用细分
modifier even though you've got two
修饰语 即使你有两个
levels here it will always use just the
级别 它将始终只使用
viewport so your render amount here
视口中的渲染量在此处
could be whatever but when you hit apply
可以是任何形式 但当你点击应用时
it's just going to apply whatever is in
它只是要应用中的任何内容
the viewport so I'm going to go two
这个视窗 所以我要看两个
levels and hit apply now look at
关卡和点击应用现在查看
this we have 16 times the detail because
这个细节是我们的16倍 因为
we had uh level one which would be 4X a
我们有 呃 第一级 是4Xa
4X uh multiply and then 4X of 4X 16 so
4x呃相乘 然后是4x 16的4x
we have 16 times the vertices to play
我们有16倍的顶点可以玩
with so now when we go into sculpt mode
现在 当我们进入雕刻模式时
look at it now when we sculpt look at
现在当我们雕刻的时候看它
that so much more room to work with um
更多的工作空间 嗯
and much more fun so now that I'm in
更有趣的是 现在我加入了
that state I'm going to just do little
在这种情况下 我只会做很少的事情
circles with this brush on each of these
用这把刷子在每一个上面画圈
points here and the reason I'm doing
这里的要点和我这么做的原因
like little circles like this is that uh
像这样的小圆圈就是那个
by default the stroke state is uh what
默认情况下 笔划状态是什么
is it space um you can switch it to
是空间 嗯 你可以切换到
airbrush if you you want and then you
如果你想要喷枪 然后你
can just click and hold it there but I
只需点击并按住它 但我
find that to actually be like harder to
发现这实际上更难做到
control so I just keep it in space mode
控件 因此我只需将其保持在空间模式
and then just do like little circles and
然后就像做小圆圈一样
then that enables you to just kind of
这样就能让你有点
continue add adding more pressure as you
继续添加添加更多压力
move your mouse so a little circle like
将鼠标移动到一个像这样的小圆圈
that and there you go very quickly
这样 你就可以很快地走了
already we have a more
我们已经有了更多
interesting uh looking shape across it
有趣的 呃 看起来像是它的形状
so another brush another tool I guess
所以我猜是另一把刷子 另一把工具
you call is it a brush or I think it's
你说它是刷子 还是我认为它是
technically I cool brushes but anyways
从技术上讲 我会冷却刷子 但不管怎样
another one that you use all the time is
你经常使用的另一个词是
grab um and conveniently it's the hotkey
抓紧 嗯 方便的是它是热键
G and what this does is just like
它的作用就像是
pushing clay with your finger it's
用你的手指推粘土
like it's really cool and the reason I'm
就像这真的很酷 而我之所以
doing this is I'm actually just uh
这样做是因为我实际上只是
exaggerating uh the design um because
夸大这个设计这个是因为
that is what makes appealing design it's
这就是吸引人的设计的原因
exaggerating uh the addition and
夸张地说 呃 增加和
subtraction that you see in a in a shape
你在一个形状中看到的减法
even though in the real world you might
即使在现实世界中你可能
not see this like tapered thing like
我不认为这是一种渐进式的东西
that um because it's got this bulous end
嗯 因为它有一个巨大的结尾
you want to draw more attention to that
你想引起更多的注意吗？
kind of globule at the end there um and
末端有一种球状物 嗯 还有
to do that yeah if you just make this a
要做到这一点 是的 如果你把它变成一个
little bit tapered using this tool it
使用这个工具可以稍微变细一点
can do that and we get to learn about a
可以做到这一点 我们就可以了解到
new tool and blender which is the whole
新的工具和搅拌机 这是整个
point of this tutorial so yeah all right
本教程的要点是 是的 好的
pull this around pull this
把这个拉过来拉这个
around just clicking dragon click and
周围只需点击一下龙就可以了
drag I could change the shape size of
拖拽我可以改变形状大小
the brush with f and um you've got more
与f和嗯你有更多的刷子
time than me so maybe make this better
时间比我长 所以也许能让这一切变得更好
than what I'm doing really quickly but
比我做得更快 但是
just get you know generally a shape like
只是让你了解一下一般的形状 比如
that and it should look a little
它看起来应该有一点
nicer okay so now let's do that uh
更好的 好的 现在我们开始吧 呃
raised Edge all the way around the rim
沿边缘一直凸起的边缘
of this now in previous versions of this
在此之前的版本中
tutorial I said just use the inflate
教程 我说只要用充气
brush and then just like draw across it
刷一刷 然后就像在上面画画一样
the problem with this is that this is so
这样做的问题是 这是如此
imprecise and you can accidentally like
不精确 你可能会意外地喜欢上
draw over another bit and then you look
再画上一点 然后你就会看到
at it side on and you get these like
在它的一侧 你会看到这些
noticeable like divots across the donut
像甜甜圈上的草皮一样引人注目
and it's not very uh it's very hard to
而且这并不是很呃很难
do cuz you keep like accidentally
是不是因为你无意中保留了
clicking off it and then on it and you
点击它 然后点击它 你就可以
get this like Jagged like dig dig dig
把这弄得像挖坑一样挖
dig dig it's not very appealing the
挖吧 它不是很吸引人
point is uh so let's go back we can
重点是 呃 让我们回去吧 我们可以
learn about another tool it's a it's
了解另一种工具 它是一个它是
another excuse to learn about another
又一个了解他人的借口
tool and that tool is called The Mask
工具 这个工具被称为面具
tool so it's actually in the list here
工具 所以它实际上在列表中
but I never remember what it is it's
但我从来不记得那是什么
just hit M M for mask and it's this one
只需按下M-M代表面具 就是这个
and what this enables you to do is uh if
这使你能够做的是 呃 如果
you just draw on it you get this gray uh
你只要在上面画 你就会得到这个灰色的 呃
shape right and then when you're using
塑造正确的形状 然后当你使用
another tool like say you switch to the
另一种工具 比如切换到
inflate brush now and if you draw over
现在就充气画笔 如果你画的话
this let me just increase this yeah if
这让我可以增加这个是的 如果
you drew over this you can see it's it's
你画了这个 你可以看到这是这是
applying an inflation to everything
把通货膨胀加到所有东西上
except the area that is dark um and
除了那片黑暗的区域
that's how you can create like you know
这就是你如何创造出你所知道的
a skin lesion on a zombie or something
僵尸身上的皮损之类的
like that um so a mask is very useful in
就像那个 嗯 所以面具在
sculpting used a lot and we're going to
雕塑用得很多 我们要
use it in just this case what we're
在这种情况下使用它 我们就是
going to do is mask out just this area
接下来要做的就是遮盖住这片区域
along the rim there and then we're going
沿着边沿那里 然后我们要去
to apply a constant inflate value to
将恒定充气值应用于
just the area that we've masked so first
就是我们首先遮盖的区域
use the mask tool mask and it doesn't
使用蒙版工具蒙版 它不会
really make sense to use like a half
使用一半真的很有意义
opaque mask so we're going to set the
不透明的面具 所以我们要设置
strength all the way to one and then
全力以赴只为一 然后
I'll use a brush size about here so
我会用大约这里大小的刷子 所以
essentially where do I want the
从本质上讲 我想要将
inflation like do I want this much
通货膨胀就像我想要的那样吗？
inflation on the rim no probably
边缘的通货膨胀不太可能
something about here and then I'm just
关于这里的一些事情 然后我只是
going to
要去
paint a darkened value all the way
一路上都涂上较暗的值
across it and I just want to make sure
穿过它 我只是想确保
that it's you know fairly even doesn't
你知道 这甚至不是
have to be completely perfect but fairly
必须是完全完美但公平的
even across it and and I obviously don't
即使在它的另一边 我显然不会
want it to be in this part because that
我想把它放在这部分 因为
you know the liquid has flowed all the
你知道液体已经流出了所有
way down and it's broken the trail and
往下走 它打破了小路
it's gone down there so I don't want any
它掉下去了 所以我不想要
raised area there um and again I
那里隆起的面积 嗯 又一次我
apologize if this look like tedious but
如果这看起来很乏味 我道歉 但是
it's a it's it's a way to learn blender
这是一种这是一种学习搅拌机的方法
piece by piece okay hey hey speaking of
一件一件好的嘿嘿说到
which um I
哪个 嗯 我
forgot with the uh sculpt Tools in
我忘了里面的雕刻工具了
blender for whatever reason it has
搅拌机 不管它有什么原因
assumed by default that you might want
默认情况下假定您可能想要
to sculpt on the other side side of your
在你的另一边雕刻
mesh so you can see I've got this smear
所以你可以看到我有这个污点
here um and that's because somewhere I
在这里 嗯 那是因为我在某个地方
was painting over here I went through
我在这里画画的时候
the mesh and it painted on the other
网格和它在另一面上画的
side of the mesh over there very
在那边的网状物的一侧非常
annoying so um I can undo it it's just
太烦人了 所以我可以解开 只是
easier than like repainting that whole
比重新粉刷要容易得多
thing and what you want to do with your
以及你想要用你的
M tool is underneath brush set it to
M工具位于画笔下方 请将其设置为
front faces only and that means when you
仅限正面 这意味着当你
paint it should mean that as you draw oh
画吧 应该就是你画的那个哦
it will it okay it could still happen
它会没事的 它仍然有可能发生
just be careful uh but it should happen
只是要小心 呃 但这是应该发生的
less it shouldn't happen like on the
更少它不应该发生像在
opposite side of the same mesh anyways
无论如何 同一网格的反面
it should happen less um by the way I
它应该发生得更少 呃 顺便说一句 我
didn't call it out cuz it's not
我没有把它叫出来 因为它不是
essential but if you do ever want to
必不可少的 但如果你想
isolate uh and only see the selected
隔离 并且只看到选定的
object uh forward slash is the isolation
对象 呃 正斜杠是孤立的
mode uh so forward slash on the number
模式 呃 所以数字上的正斜杠
pad or the actual normal keyboard will
Pad或实际的正常键盘将
pull you in and out of that state anyway
不管怎样 把你拉进拉出那个状态
so now with the mask brush with front
所以现在用前面的面具刷子
faces only enabled uh I can paint along
只有启用的脸 呃 我可以跟着画
it and uh and it should it should happen
它和 呃 如果它应该发生的话
less
较少
essentially all right um I don't know
基本上没问题 嗯 我不知道
what to say but this doesn't take long
怎么说呢 但这不会花很长时间
once you've uh once you've set it
一旦你 呃 一旦你设置好了
up and assuming you've got the strength
站起来 假设你有足够的力量
of one by the way you don't want to have
顺便说一句 你不想要一个
areas with like half opaque right cuz we
有一半不透明的区域 因为我们
want to have a constant value across it
我想要它有一个恒定值
as we inflate it and we should get a
当我们给它充气的时候 我们应该得到一个
nice raised Edge that goes all the way
漂亮的凸边 可以一直走下去
along the donut okay okay great just
沿着甜甜圈 好的 好的 很好 只是
clean it off if you got any areas that
如果你有任何地方 把它擦干净
look a little untiy a little
看起来有点不整洁
uned
未添加的
um yep awesome all right so as I
嗯 太棒了 好吧 我也是
mentioned the mask will uh actually mask
提到了面具 呃 实际上会掩盖
out the area um so you can't paint on it
离开这个区域 嗯 这样你就不能在上面画画了
we obviously want to only paint on the
我们显然只想在
area that we mask so we want to invert
我们遮罩的区域 因此我们要反转
it by just hitting control I same hotkey
它只需按下Ctrl和相同的热键
as Photoshop Etc and then obviously if
例如Photoshop等 然后很明显如果
we went to the inflate brush and then we
我们去了充气刷子 然后我们
just painted like yes we're only now
只是画得像是的 我们现在才
painting onto that area but it also
画在那个区域上 但它也
doesn't solve our problem of like
并不能解决我们的问题
different values across it so we want to
不同的价值观 所以我们想要
apply a uniform inflation on just these
对这些产品实行统一的通货膨胀
areas so there is a tool in the sculpt
区域 所以在雕刻中有一个工具
tools
工具
called where is it mesh
名为Where is It Mesh
filter so I will be honest it's probably
过滤器 所以老实说 很可能是
the laziest implementation of a tool in
中最懒惰的工具实现
blend like mesh filters are not really
像网格滤镜一样的混合并不是真的
well documented you kind of have to just
有很好的记录 你必须只是
learn how they work but unlike all these
了解它们是如何工作的 但与所有这些不同
other brushes here the way this one
这里的其他刷子就像这个一样
works is it's applying a uniform value
起作用的是它应用了一个统一的值
to the entire mesh so it doesn't
添加到整个网格 这样它就不会
actually matter where you click on the
实际上重要的是你在哪里点击
mesh um it's going to apply it and it's
网格 嗯 它将应用它 它是
applying what is in the filter types
应用过滤器类型中的内容
listed here so if I just click this is
在这里列出 所以如果我点击这是
the other thing you have to learn if I
另一件你必须学习的事情是 如果我
drag to the right I'm inflating if I
向右拖动我在膨胀 如果我
drag to the left I'm deflating and sort
拖到左边我在泄气 然后分类
of subtracting the opposite direction um
减去相反方向的
you just kind of have to learn that
你只是需要学到这一点
that's how this specific tool works my
这就是我的这个特定工具的工作原理
theory is by the way to go on a rant
顺便说一句 理论就是在大喊大叫
zbrush's user experience and interface
ZBrush的用户体验和界面
is so Arcane so badly hodg Podge
是如此神秘 霍奇波奇
together from ideas over the last two
来自过去两年的想法
decades they never had any thought in
几十年来 他们从未想过
the process they just lumped it all in
他们只是把这一切都归结为一个过程
there and blender sculpting tools
那里有搅拌机雕刻工具
competes with that so they're like hey
与之竞争 所以他们会说嘿
yeah the uh filter tools yeah they're
是的 呃 过滤工具 是的 它们是
not the easiest to understand but at
不是最容易理解的 但在
least we're not
至少我们不是
zbrush that's my uh that's my theory
ZBrush 那是我的 呃 那是我的理论
it's my working Theory I'm going with
我支持的是我的工作理论
but anyways point is is now that we're
但不管怎样 现在的重点是我们
in this you could see we're applying a
在这里 您可以看到我们正在应用一个
uniform value to everything hoay for us
对一切事物的统一价值为我们所用
um I might also I'm going to set the
嗯 我可能也会 我要把
strength of this to 0.1 and that just
将这个强度增加到0.1 然后
means that as I move the cursor it's
意味着当我移动光标时
applying less of a value for the for the
将较小的值应用于
movement so I can use smaller movements
移动 这样我就可以使用更小的移动
the other thing though is this is a
不过 另一件事是 这是一个
little like it almost looks if we go
如果我们去的话看起来有点像
into object mode looks like a tube
进入对象模式看起来像一根管子
almost around the edge of it it's not
几乎在它的边缘 它不是
very nice um it basically the edge that
很好 嗯 基本上就是边缘
we've got here is too hard so we can
我们在这里太难了 所以我们可以
smooth out that edge by using mask
用蒙版把那个边缘弄平
smooth mask okay now if we use the
现在 如果我们使用
inflate just towards to the right a
向右充气
little
一点儿
bit I'm just going to go with that let's
我只想这么做 我们就这样吧
go object mode and see how that
进入对象模式 看看它如何
looks that's pretty good I might
看起来挺好的 我可能会
actually go just a little bit more just
实际上再往前走一点
exaggerate it slightly
稍微夸张一点
more there we go great so
更多 我们走得很好 所以
yeah that's roughly it now there's a
是的 大概就是这样 现在有一个
little bit of artifacting there cuz the
有点做作 因为
the way the mask works is it's kind of
面具的工作方式是它的一种
that Feathering thing it's not very
那个长羽毛的东西它不是很
exact and it's kind of got some values
准确地说 它有一定的价值
in between it so we can smooth that out
在它之间 所以我们可以把它弄平
in sculp mode by first of all just
在雕像模式下 首先
clearing the mask and then using the
清除掩码 然后使用
smooth
光滑
tool um by default it's too high so just
工具 默认情况下 它太高了 所以
turn it down and I'm just going to
把音量关小点 我正要
smooth that edge and that'll just sort
把边缘弄平 这样就可以了
of clear up some of this artifacting
清理掉一些人为的东西
it's a little too high for whatever
对任何人来说都有点太高了
reason the smooth tool which also you
推理也是你的流畅工具
can access at any point when you're in
您可以在任何时间访问
sculp mode just by holding down shift
只需按住Shift键即可雕刻模式
and it'll temporarily uh invoke the
它会暂时呃调用
smooth tool and uh it'll use the value
平滑工具 呃 它将使用值
that is on the smooth tool so you'll be
这是在平滑工具上 所以你会
in this mode and then you hold down
在这种模式下 然后按住
shift and it'll actually not bring use
移动它 它实际上不会带来任何用处
this value but the value that's on the
这个值 而不是
smooth tool um again zbrush is the
平滑工具嗯再一次ZBrush是
competitor so some things are a little
竞争对手 所以有些事情有点
weird here anyways um so it's a little
不管怎么说 这里很奇怪 嗯 所以有点
too high just turn it down and now we've
太高了 把它调低一点 现在我们已经
got a nice value and I'm just smoothing
得到了很好的价值 我只是在平滑
this out to just clear up some of the
这只是为了清理一些
artifacting all the
艺术化所有
way
方式
around the
各地
mesh B boop
网状B boop
boop and that's it lovely hey if you've
砰的一声 就是这样可爱的嘿 如果你有
made it this far 3D is in the carts it's
走到这一步 3D已经在购物车里了
for you because uh we've done some
因为呃我们已经做了一些
fairly complex things so if you're a
相当复杂的事情所以如果你是一个
beginner and you're just getting started
初学者 您才刚刚开始
in blender congrats um because it is a
在搅拌机中恭喜嗯 因为它是一个
steep learning curve but you have
陡峭的学习曲线 但你有
learned some very complex modeling and
学习了一些非常复杂的建模
uh some sculpting so congrats you've
呃 一些雕塑 恭喜你
made it this far why not continue on the
走到这一步为什么不继续
series click here to see the next video
系列单击此处查看下一个视频
and I will see you in that PO
我会在那个PO里见到你